My name's Shinichi Kudo.
اسمي كودو شينتشي
I'm a famous high school detective who's solved countless cases!
مُتحرٍّ في الثانوية حلّ الكثير من القضايا
I solved a roller coaster murder case with no difficulty at all,
حللتُ قضية قتل أفعوانية بلا أيّ صعوبة
but then a mysterious organization forced me to take a strange poison.
لكن أجبرتني منظمة غامضة على تجرّع سمٍّ غريب
Things looked really bad!
!الوضع سيّئ بحق
Ran! What's going to happen to me?!
!ران! ما الذي سيحلّ بي؟
Are you alright, little boy?!
أأنت بخير أيّها الصبي الصغير؟
Little boy?
صبيّ صغير؟
What're these guys talking about?
ما الذي يتكلمان عنه؟
I'm a 2nd year high school student!
أنا في السنة الثانية في الثانوية
How did you get that cut on your head?!
كيف أُصبت بالجرح على رأسك؟
Cut?
جرح؟
Oh yeah!
!صحيح
A man dressed in black hit me and...
...ضربني الرجل برداء أسود
What the...?
ماذا؟
We've found an injured boy.
وجدنا صبيّاً مُصاباً
Yes, he's a grade school student.
أجل، إنّه تلميذ في الابتدائية
Who's a grade school student?!
!من التلميذ في الابتدائية؟
What're they talking about?!
!ما الذي يتكلم عنه؟
These officers are acting strange!
!هذان الضابطان يتصرفان بغرابة
There may have been an incident-- he's received injuries to his head.
ربما وقعت حادثة، هناك إصابة برأسه
Where did he go?!
!أين ذهب الفتى؟
We may have a crime on our hands! Try to find him!
!قد تكون لدينا جريمة هنا! ابحث عنه
Right!
!أجل
Mori Detective Agency
وكالة موري للتحرّي
I'm home!
عُدت
Oh, you're back, Ran!
!رجعتِ يا ران
Come on, Dad, can't you stop throwing trash all over?
!يا إلهي يا أبي! كفّ عن رمي القمامة هكذا
This is why you don't get any jobs! And why Mom ran out on you!
!لهذا لا تتلقى أيّ طلبات عمل! ولهذا تركتك أمّي
I choose what jobs I take.
أنا أختار الأعمال التي أقبلها
Anyway, where's that so-called detective of yours?
بأيّ حال، أين ذاك الفتى الذي يلعب لعبة المتحرّي؟
Wasn't he with you?
ألم يكن معك؟
He was before we left the amusement park.
كان كذلك قبل مغادرتنا حديقة الملاهي
But then...
...لكن عندها
Sorry, Ran! You go on ahead!
!آسف يا ران! ارجعي قبلي
What could Shinichi be doing?
ما الذي يفعله شينتشي؟
I haven't run that far, so why am I so out of breath?!
لم أركض مسافةً طويلة، ومع ذلك أنفاسي منقطعة
I-I've shrunk!
!تـ-تقلّص جسدي
How?!
!كيف؟
Wait, it couldn't be...
...لحظة، أيمكن
We'll use this. Our organization's latest poison.
سنستعمل هذا، آخر سمّ طوّرته منظمتنا
Could it be because I swallowed that pill?!
!أيمكن لأنّي تجرّعت ذاك العقار؟
Hello, this is Shinichi Kudo.
مرحباً، أنا كودو شينتشي
I'm away at the moment.
لستُ موجوداً هذه اللحظة
If you're interested in hiring me, please leave your name and number...
،إن كنت مهتماً بطلب خدماتي فاترك اسمك ورقمك من فضلك
That's strange. He's still not home.
غريب، لم يعد للبيت بعد
He's probably out havin' dinner with his novelist dad or somethin'...
إنّه يتناول العشاء مع أبيه الروائيّ في مطعم حتماً
Shinichi's parents moved to America three years ago,
انتقل والدا شينتشي لأمريكا قبل 3 أعوام
so he's living all by himself now!
!ويعيش بمفرده الآن
Oh yeah?
صحيح، هكذا إذاً
Something must've happened to him afterward!
لا بدّ أنّ أمراً حلّ به بعدها
I'm going to stop by his house!
!سأذهب لمنزله
W-What about my dinner?!
!لحظة! ماذا عن عشائي؟
Darn it! Can't I even get into my own house?!
!تبّاً! لا يمكنني دخول منزلي حتّى؟
Professor Agasa!
!بروفسور آغاسا
Who are you?
من أنت؟
It's me! Shinichi!
!إنّه أنا! شينتشي
A relative of Shinichi, are you?
قريب لشينتشي؟
His house is the next one over.
منزله هو المجاور
I'm Shinichi!
!أنا شينتشي
Here, I'll prove it!
!سأخبرك عمَّ أعرفه عنك إذاً
Your name is Hiroshi Agasa and you're 52!
!اسمك آغاسا هيروشي، 52 عاماً
You're an eccentric inventor and claim that you're a genius,
أنت مخترع غريب الأطوار وتدّعي أنّك عبقري
but everything you make is junk!
!لكن كلّ ما تصنعه هو خردة
You also have a mole on your butt that has a hair sticking out of it!
!كما لديك شامة على مؤخرتك بشعرة بارزة
Only Shinichi knows about that!
!شينتشي وحده يعرف ذلك
He's been spreading my secrets around, has he?
ينشر أسراري بين الناس إذاً
No! It's because I'm Shinichi!
!كلا! أعرف لأنّي شينتشي
I was forced to take some weird pill which made my body shrink!
!أُجبرت على تجرّع عقار غريب وتقلّص جسدي
A pill that shrunk you?
عقار قلّص جسدك؟
Yeah!
!أجل
I highly doubt any such pills exist!
!أشكّ كثيراً بوجود هكذا عقار
You suspicious little punk! I'm taking you to the police!
!أيّها الشقي المريب! سآخذك للشرطة
Professor! You tripped while hurrying
بروفسور! تعثرت في طريق عودتك مسرعاً
on your way back from the Colombo restaurant, didn't you?!
من مطعم كولومبو، أليس كذلك؟
How do you know that?!
كـ-كيف تعرف؟
Your clothes, Professor.
ملابسك يا بروفسور
The front of your clothes are still wet, yet the back is completely dry!
مُقدمة ثيابك لا تزال مُبللة، بينما الجانب الخلفي جاف تماماً
That's evidence that you were running in the rain.
هذا دليلٌ على أنك كنت تركض في المطر
What's more, you also have mud on your pants.
كما هناك وحل على بنطالك
The only street in this area where you could get mud on you
الشارع الوحيد الموحل في هذه المنطقة
is in front of Colombo, which is under construction!
!هو ذاك قيد الإنشاء أمام كولومبو
Plus some of Colombo's special meat sauce is still in your mustache.
كما لا تزال صلصة لحم كولومبو الخاصة عالقة على شاربيك
W-Who are you?
مـ-من أنت؟
Elementary, my dear Agasa!
!هذا بسيط يا آغاسا-كن
S-Shinichi?
شـ-شينتشي؟
I see.
هكذا إذاً
So, the uncompleted poison mysteriously caused your body to shrink.
السم غير المكتمل قلّص جسدك بشكل غامض
That's the gist of it.
هذه فحوى الموضوع
Talk about lame. My clothes from when I was a kid fit perfectly.
يا للسخافة، ملابسي من صغري تلائمني تماماً
I'm begging you, Professor! You are a genius, after all!
أرجوك يا بروفسور! أنت عبقري، أليس كذلك؟
Make me some medicine that'll change me back to normal!
!اصنع دواءً يعيدني لطبيعتي
Hold on there! I don't even know the ingredients of the pill you took...
رويدك! لا أعرف مكوّنات العقار الذي تجرعته حتّى
Then all we need to do is figure out where those guys are
كلّ ما علينا فعله هو العثور عليهم إذاً
and get some of those pills!
!ثمّ أخذ ذاك العقار
Well, that would certainly help...
حسناً، سيساعد ذلك حتماً
Listen, Shinichi!
اسمع يا شينتشي
If they find out you're still alive,
إن عرفوا أنّك لا تزال حيّاً
they'll come back to put an end to you for good!
سيعودون للقضاء عليك
So, this must stay a secret between just the two of us!
!لذا أبقِ ما حصل سرّاً بيننا فقط
You mustn't tell anyone at all!
!إيّاك أن تخبر أحداً
That means not even Ran-kun!
!حتّى ران-كن بالطبع
Shinichi! Are you there?!
شينتشي! أأنت موجود؟
It's Ran!
!إنّها ران
Oh no! Hide quickly!
!كلا! اختبئ بسرعة
If you're home, then you can at least answer the phone!
!إن كنت في المنزل فأجب على الهاتف على الأقل
Huh? Professor Agasa? Where's Shinichi?
ماذا؟ بروفسور آغاسا؟ أين شينتشي؟
Uh, well, he's...
...في الواقع، إنّه
Dad's glasses...
نظّارات أبي
Disguise time!
!وقت التنكر
He isn't here?
ليس هنا؟
Whoa, these are strong!
!إنّها حادة
Huh? Is there someone there?
ماذا؟ أهناك أحد؟
You must be really shy!
لا بد أنّك خجول حقاً
Come on now, face this way!
هيّا، التفت لي
He's...
...إ-إنّه
...so cute!
!ظريفٌ جداً
Her chest!
صدرها
Who is this boy?
من هذا الصبيّ؟
He belongs to a distant relative of mine!
إنّه ابن قريبٍ بعيد الصلة لي
What's your name?
ما اسمك؟
M-My name's Shin-
...ا-اسمي شينـ
Err...
...أقصد
Conan!
!كونان
My name's Conan Edogawa!
!اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
Conan? That's an odd name.
كونان؟ اسمٌ غريب
My dad was a big fan of Conan Doyle, so...
...كان أبي مُعجباً كبيراً بكونان دويل، لذا
Reminds me of Shinichi somehow...
يذكّرني بشينتشي نوعاً ما
Oh, Ran-kun, I almost forgot!
!صحيح يا ران-كن
Do you think you could let him stay at your house for a little while?
أيمكنك تركه يقيم في منزلك لبعض الوقت؟
What the heck are you...?
...ما الذي تقولـ
His parents are in the hospital after getting into an accident.
والداه في المشفى بعد تعرّضهما لحادث
They asked me to look after him, but I live a bachelor's life, so...
...طلبا مني رعايته، لكنّي رجلٌ بمفردي فلذا
Sure, but I'll have to ask my dad first.
لا بأس، لكنّي سأسأل أبي أوّلاً
Right! So, you're willing to take him in?
أجل! لا تمانعين أخذه إذاً؟
Isn't that great news, Conan?
أليس هذا رائعاً يا كونان؟
What happens if Ran finds out who I really am while I'm there?!
ماذا لو كشفت ران هويّتي وأنا هناك؟
The first step to turning you back to normal
أوّل خطوة لإعادتك لطبيعتك
is finding the men in black who used that drug on you!
هي العثور على الرجال بالرداء الأسود الذين استعملوا العقار عليك
And Ran-kun's house is a detective agency!
!ومنزل ران-كن وكالة تحرٍّ
Her dad might run across information about them!
!قد تمرّ على أبيها معلومات عنهم
Exactly!
!تماماً
Say, Conan-kun...
أخبرني يا كونان-كن
Yeah?
أجل؟
I'll never get used to this name!
لن أعتاد على هذا الاسم أبداً
Is there anyone you like?
أيوجد أحد تحبّه؟
Like a girl at school or someone?
فتاة في المدرسة وما شابه
No, none at all.
كلا، لا لديّ
There's someone I really like, though!
أنا أملك شخصاً يعجبني كثيراً
Don't tell me it's that Shinichi boy you were looking for earlier?
أيمكن أنّه شينتشي-نيتشان الذي كنتِ تبحثين عنه قبل قليل؟
That's right!
صحيح
He's always been kind of a tease since he was a kid,
لطالما كان مزعجاً مُذ صغره
and he's always been so full of himself and a big mystery geek,
ومغترّاً كثيراً بنفسه
but he's also courageous, cool, and dependable!
ومهووس تحرٍّ، لكنه أهل للثقة متى استدعت الحاجة، كما رائعٌ وشجاع
I really like Shinichi a lot!
أنا أُحب شينتشي كثيراً
But keep this a secret from him!
لكن أبقِ هذا سرّاً عنه
Here we are! This is my house!
هذا هو منزلي
It's almost like I've gained a cute little brother!
أشعر كأنّي حصلت على أخ صغير ظريف
It's like I can talk to you about anything, Conan-kun!
كأن بإمكاني الكلام معك في أيّ شيء يا كونان-كن
Ran...
...ران
Let me introduce you to my dad! Follow me!
سأعرّفك على أبي، اتبعني
Um, Ran...
...ران، أنا
I-I'm actually...
...فـ-في الواقع
I'm really...
...أنا
I got one! I got one!
!أتى! أتى! أتى
Dad!
!أبي
My first job in 6 months!
!أوّل عمل لي في 6 أشهر
Someone kidnapped a rich guy's daughter!
!اختطف أحدهم ابنة رجلٍ ثري
Some guy dressed in black!
!شخص برداء أسود
A man dressed in black?!
!شـ-شخص برداء أسود؟
Taxi!
!تاكسي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
This case is calling my name!
هذه القضية تناديني
Calling for the famous detective known as Kogoro Mori!
!المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
Why are you here?!
!لمَ أنتِ هنا؟
Because he got in before I could stop him!
!لأنّه صعد قبل أن أتمكن من إيقافه
I'm riding in a car! Yay!
!أنا في سيّارة! مرحى
So, who is he?!
!ومن هذا الفتى؟
He belongs to a relative of Professor Agasa!
!إنّه لقريب للبروفسور آغاسا
I don't need you bothering me while I work! Get out!
!لا تعترضا عملي! اخرجا
We can't get out! We're on a freeway!
!لا يمكننا! نحن في الخطّ السريع
The person kidnapped was my only daughter.
المُختطفة هي ابنتي الوحيدة
Akiko Tani. 10 years old.
تاني أكيكو، 10 أعوام
My butler Asao saw the perpetrator with his own eyes.
رأى كبير خدمي أساو الفاعل بأم عينيه
Darn, I can't see the picture.
تبّاً، لا أستطيع رؤية الصورة
Being so small is such a pain!
قصر القامة مزعج حقّاً
What was the surrounding situation like when she was kidnapped?
ما كانت الظروف المحيطة عندما اختُطفت؟
Who is this boy?
من هذا الصبيّ؟
Just an acquaintance...
...أحد المعارف فقط
Ran! Watch him!
!ران! راقبيه
Well then, Asao-san, please explain in detail what happened.
إذاً يا آساو-سان، اشرح ما حصل بالتفصيل رجاءً
It occurred when she went to play outside after returning from school.
وقعت الحادثة بعدما ذهبت للهو في الخارج بعد عودتها من المدرسة
A man dressed in black suddenly appeared from a corner of the garden!
!ظهر رجل برداء أسود فجأةً من زاوية الحديقة
Give this message to her father.
أخبر ربّ البيت بهذه الرسالة
If he wants his daughter back, he'll shut down his company for 1 month.
إن أراد عودة ابنته، فليغلق شركته شهراً كاملاً
Get the police involved and she's as good as dead!
!وإن أبلغ الشرطة فستفقد حياتها بالطبع
Upon leaving those words,
،بعد قول هذا
the kidnapper scaled a pine tree and escaped outside!
تسلّق المختطف شجرة الصنوبر وهرب للخارج
Did this man have any special characteristics?
أكان بذاك الرجل أيّ علامات مميّزة؟
My eyes aren't what they used to be, so...
...نظري ليس كما كان عليه، لذا
That's too bad...
هذا مؤسف
You shouldn't get in the way of my dad's work, Conan-kun...
لا تتدخل في عمل أبي يا كونان-كن
Did anyone else hear the kidnapper's voice or any sounds out of the ordinary?
بالمناسبة، أسمع أيّ أحد آخر صوت المختطِف أو أيّ صوت غريب؟
No. Other than Asao-san's shouts for help, it was completely quiet.
كلا، كان الصمت مخيماً باستثناء صرخات آساو-سان طلباً للنجدة
Which means Asao-san was the only one who saw the perpetrator.
مما يعني أنّ آساو-سان وحده من رأى الفاعل
Judging from the demands, the kidnapper is likely someone from a rival company.
بناءً على طلبه، من المُرجّح أن المختطِف موظّف من شركة منافسة
Damn it! To think they would want money on top of that demand!
!تبّاً! يريدون مالاً فوق طلبهم ذاك
Money?!
!مـ-مال؟
There was a phone call just now!
!وصلني اتّصال قبل قليل
They demanded that I prepare 300 million, all in used bills!
!طلب مني تحضير 300 مليون، بعملة ورقية قديمة
There must be some sort of mistake, sir!
!لا بدّ أنّه خطأ ما يا سيّدي
Silence! You will remain quiet!
!اخرس! ابق صامتاً
Which companies stand to gain something if your company shuts down?
أيّ شركات ستستفيد من إغلاق شركتك؟
There's something not right about this incident.
هناك أمرٌ غريب بهذه القضيّة
Why did the perpetrator kidnap her inside her home?
لمَ خطفها الفاعل داخل منزلها؟
It would've been easier on her way home from school.
الأمر أسهل لو اختطفها في طريقها من المدرسة
And being clearly seen is too careless.
كما رؤية أحد له إهمال كبير
But demanding used bills is oddly cautious...
...لكنّ طلب عملات قديمة إجراء حذِر غريب
Oh, you're really good at soccer, Conan-kun!
أنتَ بارع في كرة القدم يا كونان-كن
I guess so.
نوعاً ما
Shinichi would do that whenever he was thinking about something.
كان شينتشي يفعل مثلك دوماً عندما يفكر بشيء
He said it would get his mind working.
يقول أنّ هذا يحفّز دماغه للعمل
That Shinichi is me!
!شينتشي ذاك هو أنا
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
How rare it is for Jumbo to be friendly with a stranger.
من النادر أن يكون جامبو ودوداً مع غريب
The kidnapper climbed this pine tree to break in and to get out.
تسلّق الخاطف شجرة الصنوبر هذه للتسلل للداخل ثم الخروج
Which means this dog must have barked at him!
!مما يعني أنّ الكلب نبح عليه حتماً
That's it! I've figured this case out!
!فهمت! حللت هذه القضية
It sounds like this dog barks at all strangers, doesn't it?
يبدو أنّ هذا الكلب ينبح تّجاه كل الغرباء، صحيح؟
Yes. Jumbo is one of the best guard dogs around, after all.
أجل، فجامبو من أفضل كلاب الحراسة
Wait, the servants said that it was completely quiet
لحظة، قال الخدم أنّ المكان كان هادئاً تماماً
except for when the butler was yelling!
باستثناء وقت صراخ كبير الخدم
And where are you going, Asao-san?
أين تذهب يا أساو-سان؟
He realized it!
أدرك الأمر
There's something strange about your story!
!هناك أمرٌ غريب بروايتك
The kidnapper snuck in, took the girl, and escaped using that tree!
تسلل الخاطف وأخذ الفتاة وهرب عبر تلك الشجرة
Yet the guard dog didn't bark!
!مع ذلك لم ينبح كلب الحراسة أبداً
That's because...
...هـ-هذا
Plus your testimony is too full of ambiguity!
كما أنّ شهادتك مليئة بالغموض
Was there really a man dressed in black, Asao-san?
أكان هناك رجلاً موشوحاً بالسواد حقاً يا آساو-سان؟
Or shall I say, Kidnapper!
!أو بالأحرى، يا مختطِف
Asao! How dare you!
!آساو! كيف تجرؤ؟
My deepest apologies, sir!
!أقدّم خالص اعتذاري سيّدي
What did you do this for?!
!لمَ أقدمت على فعلتك؟
Did someone put you up to it?!
!أأمرك أحد؟
No, I did this entirely of my own accord!
!كلا! قمتُ بهذا من تلقاء نفسي
So, where is the girl now?
أين الفتاة الآن إذاً؟
A nearby hotel...
...في فندق بالقرب
Case closed!
!أُغلقت القضية
With Detective Kogoro Mori on the job, no case goes unsolved!
!لا قضيّة تستعصي مع المتحرّي موري كوغورو
No! It's not over yet!
!كلا! لم ينته الأمر بعد
There's still another side to this case!
!لا يزال هناك جانب آخر لهذه القضيّة
Sir! There's a phone call!
!سيّدي! هناك اتّصال
I'm busy. Tell them to call back later!
أنا مشغول. أخبريه بالاتصال لاحقاً
B-But...
...لـ-لكن
This is Tani.
تاني معك
Is the 300 million ready?
هل الثلاثمئة مليون جاهزة؟
Who is this?!
من أنت؟
I called earlier.
اتّصلت بك قبل قليل
I'm the guy who kidnapped your daughter.
أنا مُختطف ابنتك
That's impossible! The kidnapper has already...
...ذلك مُحال! المختطف بالفعل قد
So, you did have help!
!كان لديك متواطئ إذاً؟
No, I did it alone! Please believe me!
!كلا، كنت بمفردي! صدّقني رجاءً
This man is telling the truth.
هذا الرجل يقول الحقيقة
After being kidnapped for the first time,
،بعد أن اُختطفت الفتاة في أوّل مرة
she was most likely kidnapped again by someone else.
تمّ اختطافها مُجدداً من قِبل شخص آخر على الأرجح
By someone much worse!
شخص أكثر شرّاً
Daddy! Help!
!أبي! النجدة
Akiko!
!أكيكو
I'm an impatient man.
أنا رجلٌ قصير الصبر
Hurry and get the 300 million ready,
جهّز الثلاثمئة مليون سريعاً
or there's no telling what'll happen to your daughter.
وإلّا لستُ مسؤولاً عمَّ سيحلّ بابنتك
Please! I'll get the money somehow!
!أرجوك! سأجلب المال بطريقة ما
Just give Akiko back unharmed!
!أعد أكيكو سليمة فقط
Keep him talking and try to find out his location!
واصل الكلام وحاول استخراج موقعه
His location?
موقعه؟
Who's that?!
من معك؟
Don't tell me it's the police.
لا تخبرني أنّها الشرطة
No! It isn't...
...كلا! ليست الشرطة
Daddy! I'm in a storeroom of a school!
!أبي! أنا في مخزن مدرسة
I can see a big chimney from the window-
...أرى مدخنةً كبيرة من النافذة
Akiko!
!أكيكو
I'll call again in one hour.
سأعاود الاتصال في ساعة
Get the money ready by then!
لتجهّز المال حينها
Big-mouthed brat.
شقيّة ثرثارة
A big chimney visible from a school storeroom
مدخنة كبيرة يمكن رؤيتها من مخزن مدرسة
isn't enough information to pinpoint which school it is...
ليست معلومة كافية لتحديد أيّ مدرسة
At any rate, please buy us some time by preparing the money.
بأيّ حال، وفّر لنا وقتاً بتجهيز المال
R-Right!
حـ-حسناً
The kidnapper's nervous now that we know his location!
الخاطف متوتر الآن بما أنّنا مدركون لموقعه
If we don't rescue the little girl soon...
...إلم ننقذ الفتاة سريعاً
What're you doing, Conan-kun?
ماذا تفعل يا كونان-كن؟
It hasn't been very long since she was kidnapped,
لم يمرّ وقت طويل على اختطافها
so I figured they might be somewhere nearby...
فظننتُ أنّها قد تكون قريبة
That's right!
صحيح
There's no way he could have gotten far with a little girl with him!
من المحال أنّه ابتعد بفتاة صغيرة معه
If we limit it to the nearby area, that leaves only so many schools to check!
،إن قلّصنا الاحتمالات ضمن المنطقة لمجاورة ستكون مدارس معدودة
Conan-kun, where are you going?!
!أين تذهب يا كونان-كن؟
Ran! After that dog!
!ران! لنلحق بالكلب
Right!
أجل
The chimney she sees is probably either a factory or a bathhouse!
المدخنة التي تراها غالباً تعود لمصنع أو حمّام عام
There are only 5 schools in the area where you can see chimneys!
توجد 5 مدارس فقط في هذه المنطقة حيث ترى منها مداخناً
No!
!كلا
Not here either!
!ليست هذه أيضاً
Darn it! It wasn't any of them!
!تبّاً! لم تكن أيّاً منها
There aren't any other schools that have views of chimneys!
لم تبق هناك مدارس بإطلالات على مداخن
They must not be in this area after all!
لعلها ليست في هذه المنطقة بالفعل
Wait a second! Just maybe...
...لحظة، أيمكن
This is it!
!هذه هي
She saw this building from the side and mistook it for a chimney!
!رأت هذا البناء من الجانب وظنّته مدخنة
Schools in this vicinity that have a side view of this building...
...المدارس في الجوار بمنظر جانبي لهذا البناء
Futatsubashi Middle School!
!مدرسة فوتاتسوباشي الإعدادية
Place the money on the bench in Hyakujii Park.
ضع المال على المقعد في حديقة هياكوجي
Once I have it in my hands, I'll return the girl.
وسأعيد ابنتك بعدما يصبح بحوزتي
Let me hear Akiko's voice one more time!
!دعني أسمع صوت أكيكو مُجدداً
You'll have plenty of time later to hear it.
ستسمعه بما يكفي لاحقاً
We've come to an agreement.
وصلنا لاتّفاق
Which means your role is just about over with.
أي أنّ دورك انتهى تقريباً
Not so fast!
!توقف
Who's there?! Where are you?!
!من هناك؟! أين أنت؟
Right here!
!هنا
It's alright now.
أنتِ بخير الآن
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Shinichi Kudo...
كودو شينتشي
...I mean, Conan Edogawa. A detective!
أقصد... إيدوغاوا كونان، مُتحرٍّ
A detective?
مُتحرٍّ؟
Don't be mockin' me, you little brat!
!لا تستهن بي أيّها الصبيّ العفن
Darn it! I can't put any power into it with my body so small!
!تباً! قوّتي ضعيفة بهذا الجسد الضئيل
How about this?!
!ما رأيك بهذه؟
No good! My soccer kicks have weakened, too!
!لا جدوى! ضعفت قوّة ركلي أيضاً
Even if I do find the criminals,
حتّى لو وجدتُ المجرمين
in my smaller body, I can't even capture them or beat them up!
!لا يمكنني القبض عليهم أو حتّى ضربهم بجسدي الصغير
Playtime's over! Say your prayers!
!انتهى وقت اللعب! تحضّر لموتك
Stop!
!توقف
It's all over!
!سينال مني
Ran!
!ران
Talk about strong!
!قـ-قويّة
Everything's okay now!
كلّ شيء على ما يرام الآن
How did you know to come here?
كيف عرفتِ المكان؟
I followed you and then I saw Jumbo jump out from here!
لحقتُ بك ثم رأيت جامبو يخرج من هنا
Jumbo!
!جامبو
So, you're the one behind this!
!أنتَ الفاعل إذاً؟ تبّاً لك
Kidnapping case? Detective Kogoro Mori is your man!
!قضية اختطاف؟ المُتحري موري كوغورو لها
I was the one who came up with the idea to kidnap me!
كنتُ من فكّرت بحادثة اختطافي هذه
What?!
!ماذا؟
Daddy's always too busy with work to care about me...
أنت مشغول دوماً بالعمل يا أبي ...ولا تهتم لي
So, I had Asao-san "kidnap" me.
لذا طلبت من آساو-سان مساعدتي وتولّي الاختطاف
I thought I could get Daddy to spend time with me
ظننت سيمكنك قضاء وقت معي
if his company had to take a break!
!لو استرحت من شركتك قليلاً
I see. So, the first kidnapping was a fake.
فهمت، كان الاختطاف الأوّل مزيفاً إذاً
Even if my daughter did ask for your help,
،ولو كان ذلك بناء على طلب ابنتي
I find it difficult to forgive what you've done!
!من الصعب عليّ أن أصفح عمَّ فعلته
I assume you realize this, Asao?!
!تدرك ذلك يا آساو، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
As punishment,
،عقاباً لك
you will make arrangements for a 1-week trip that starts tomorrow!
!ستتولى التجهيزات لرحلة أسبوع تبدأ غداً
A trip to Australia, where Akiko has always wanted to go!
!الوجهة هي أستراليا التي لطالما أرادت أكيكو زيارتها
S-Sir!
!سـ-سيّدي
She and I will be going there together, of course!
سنذهب سويّاً بالطبع
Daddy!
!أبي
Letting the dog go so he could find my daughter was a stroke of genius.
إطلاق الكلب كي يجد ابنتي كانت حركةً عبقرية
You truly are a great detective!
كما يُتوقع من المتحري العظيم
No, it's because of all the experience I've had!
!كلا، كان ذلك بفضل تجاربي الكثيرة
Who are you to talk? I was the one who found him...
كنتُ أنا من وجدها، ما حقك بالكلام؟
I will express my gratitude to you another day.
سأعبر عن امتناني لك في يوم آخر إذاً
Right! I'm looking forward to it!
!أجل! أتطلّع لذلك
Thanks, Mr. Detective!
!شكراً لك أيّها المتحري
Mr. Detective?
المتحري؟
No, she means him, not me!
!كلا، لا تقصدني
Say, Dad, about this boy...
أبي، بشأن هذا الفتى
Professor Agasa asked if we would take care of him...
طلب مني البروفسور آغاسا الاعتناء به
You're against it?
لستَ موافقاً؟
Sure thing!
!لا مشكلة
I got a job the instant he showed up, and then I solved it like an ace!
حصلت على عمل حال ظهوره ثم حللت القضية بكلّ براعة
He just might be a god of good fortune!
!قد يكون إله حظّ حسن
Stay with us and become my son!
!ابقَ معنا وكن ابني
I just transferred here! My name's Conan Edogawa!
!انتقلتُ هنا للتو! اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
Nice to meet you!
!سُررت بلقائكم
I have to go back to grade school again?
عليّ العودة للابتدائية؟
The one responsible...
...الفاعل
...is you!
!هو أنت
If Shinichi were here, he'd easily solve this case.
لو كان شينتشي هنا، لحلّ هذه القضية بسهولة
Where could that mystery nerd have gone?
أين ذهب مهووس التحرّي ذاك؟
Hot!
!حارّ
Mori-kun! You were right!
!موري-كن! كنتَ محقاً
I've changed my mind about you, "Great Detective"!
!تغيّرت نظرتي تجاهك أيّها المتحري العظيم
I could never do that. I could never be as strong as Yoko-san...
...لا يمكنني أن أكون قويّةً مثلك يا يوكو-سان
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
A Murder Behind the Locked Doors of a Celebrity's Apartment.
جريمة قتل خلف أبواب مغلقة لشقّة الفنّانة
Next Conan's Hint:
:تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Ice.
ثلج
Think you can beat me next time?
هل ستستطيعون التغلّب عليّ الحلقة القادمة؟